live.
Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded the
whole world to keep. Brother James.
Yes, sir. And God spake all these words,
saying, I am the Lord thy God, which
have brought thee out of the land of
Egypt, out of the house of bondage. Thou
shalt have no other gods before me. Thou
shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above, or that is in the
earth beneath, or that is in the water
under the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Sixth day shalt thou labor
and do all thy work, but the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work, thou nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hallowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shalt not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou
shalt not steal. Thou shalt not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shalt not covet thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
wife, nor as man's servant, nor as
maid's servant, nor as ox, nor as ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbors. I
read Exodus 20:es 1-17.
May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of this word. In Jesus' name we
pray. Amen.
Amen.
Amen. Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the long and vague
questions. We are only here to bring the
true gospel of Jesus and we are not here
to debate. So, please be as direct as
possible with your questions so we can
be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bibles. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind this is a live stream, so feel
free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you keep them to a two
scripture maximum. But let me introduce
to you the family that's on the panel
this evening. We got brother Jerome.
Grace and peace.
We got brother Dre.
Good evening.
We got brother Julius.
Good evening everybody.
We got brother James.
Good evening everyone.
Sister Deborah.
Good evening.
And we have sister Casey and the guest
caller. And I'm brother Cornell. What is
our first question of the evening?
Uh yes. There are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Humility Israel asks in Numbers 31
17 and 18. It's being said that these
were virgins and God allowed the men to
have them sexually. Is this accurate?
All right, brother Jerome shares some
light on that numbers 317
and 18.
Um, no, it's not quite accurate. You
know, uh, uh, saying that God allow men
to take these women to have them
sexually is implying that they not
taking these women for wives. See, the
Lord's not interested in the men taking
these women
and committing whoredom with him. You
know, Lord is against that. Okay. So, uh
when you dealing with this chapter, it's
talking about when uh Israel was at war
going to war against the Midianites.
Okay? And he told the Lord told them he
wanted them to kill everybody.
The men, the women, the children, but
not the children that have not uh uh lay
with a uh uh the children, the the women
that laid with a man, man. He said, kill
them too. But the ones that didn't lay
with a man, he said, "Keep them alive
for yourselves. Not to have them as
someone that you can commit whoredom
with." No. Take them to be a wife. All
right. And so, let's go read the verse
that you gave though. Verse, what is it?
17 and 18. And that numbers
chapter 31.
Numbers 31.
Yeah. uh verses 17 and 18.
Okay. When you get it, James, go ahead
and read it.
Now therefore, kill every male among the
little ones, and kill every woman that
has known man by lying with him. But all
the women children that have not known a
man by lying with him, keep alive for
yourselves.
Yeah. not to commit hoarding with, you
know, get get you a wife from among
them. All right, but let's show you that
this talking about when uh the
Israelites were in war against the
Midianites. Okay, so skip up and read
verse 6 and 7. Then we going to skip
read verse 6 and seven.
And Moses sent to them to the war a
thousand of every tribe them and Phineas
the son of Eleazar the priest to the war
with the holy instruments and the
trumpets to blow in his hand.
And they wared against the Midianites as
the Lord commanded Moses and they slew
all the males.
Skip down to verse 9 and read it to the
18. Read it as quickly as you can.
Okay. And the children of Israel took
all the women of Midian captives, and
their little ones, and took the spoil of
all their cattle, and all their flocks,
and all their goods. And there, and they
burnt all the cities wherein they dwelt,
and all their goodly castles with fire.
And they took all the spoil, and all the
prey, both of men and of beasts. And
they brought the captives and the prey,
and the spoil unto Moses, and Eleazar
the priest, and unto the congregation of
the children of Israel, unto the camps
of the plains of Moab, which are by
Jordan near Jericho.
And Moses and Eleazar the priests, and
all the priests of the congregation,
went forth to meet them without the
camp.
Listen to what Moses Listen to what
Moses them going to say about what these
Israelites did, okay? that took these
captives.
Go ahead.
And Moses was wroth with the officers of
the host, with the captains over
thousands, and captives over hundreds,
which c which came from the battle? And
Moses said unto them, Have ye saved all
the women alive? Behold, these cause
these caused the children of Israel
through the council of Baalim to commit
trespass against the Lord in the matter
of Peor. And there was a plague among
the congregation of the Lord.
Now therefore kill every male among the
little ones, and kill every woman that
hath known man by lying with him, but
all the woman children that have not
known a man by lying with him, keep
alive for yourselves.
To take as a wife, not for someone to
lay with to commit whoredom. That That's
all I got on that.
All right, thank you for that. Hope that
answered that question as we move on to
our next one.
Moving on. Pauline R wants you to
explain Zechariah 5 verse9. Who are
these women with wings?
Women with wings in Zechariah 5 and9.
Let's go there and brother James pick it
up at that nine. The guest caller will
take it from there.
Okay. Zechariah 5:9 says, "Then lifted I
up mine eyes, and looked, and behold,
there came out two women, and the wind
was in the in their wings, for they had
wings like the wings of a stork, and
they lifted up the epha between the
earth and the heaven."
Okay, this is uh this is talking really
about the Catholic Church. Let's back up
to the fifth verse and we're going to
read the uh 5-
11.
Okay.
It says,
"Then the angel that talked with me went
forth and said unto me, Lift up now
thine eyes, and see what is this that
goeth forth." And I said,
Okay,
my screech was in my ears. Okay, start
over again.
Okay. Then the angel that talked with me
went forth and said,
"Good grief. What is that?"
That I'm not sure.
Go ahead.
Then the angel that talked with me went
forth and said unto me, "Lift up now
thine eyes, and see what is this that
goeth forth." And I said, "What is it?"
And he said, "This is an epha that goeth
forth." He said, "Moreover, this is
their resemblance
through all the earth. And behold,
this this epha, this epha, that's
actually what the Catholic Church call
the rosary." Okay.
Somebody got a little background noise
going on. Sound like a smoke alarm.
Yeah. They should me.
You got to cut that phone.
Why?
So he was saying the epha is the rosary.
That's what it represents.
Okay. So that being the case, we know
that's pointing in the direction for
sure. Pick it pick it up back up when
you get a chance, brother James. Pick it
up uh at ver back at verse nine because
he going somewhere with this.
Okay?
You know,
ver verse 9 says,
"Then lifted I up mine eyes, and looked,
and behold, there came out two women,
and the wind was in their wings, for
they had wings like the wings of a
stork, and they lifted up the epha
between the earth and the heaven." Well,
okay. You can stop right back there. So,
uh, when he gets back, is your guest
call, are you back?
Yeah. But what we want you to do,
sisters and brothers, is highlight uh,
what it says, the two women, and then
the wind was in their wings, and then
highlight for like like the wings of a
stork,
and they lifted up the epa between the
earth and the heaven.
All right, guess caller, you back with
us.
I think it's muted. So, I'm trying to
see if we can unmute.
Okay.
So, what we can do then since uh let's
let's come back for a revisit because we
were in the middle of answering that.
Sister Deborah, let's go on to our next
question and we'll come back.
Yes. Uh Sam Burns says in Drew 1 verse 6
speaks of the angels reserve in
everlasting chains.
Is that why only the tree of knowledge
of good and evil was in the garden of
Eden?
All right, Julius, tell us about this
reserved and everlasting change.
Uh the is that why only uh the tree of
knowledge of good and evil was in the
garden of Eden? No, that's not why he
was there. He was there but the other
angels were there. Uh they were there
but it just mentions him because they
were there in the earth. So these other
one-third of the angels were cast out of
heaven with Satan, the devil with him.
Let's go to Revelation the 12th chapter
and read it.
We're going to read Revelation 12:es 3
and 4.
Okay?
Because they all uh but but this was
before
in the Garden of Eden. This was before
the they were put up under the chains of
darkness. Revelation 12, read verse 3
and 4.
And there appeared another wonder in
heaven. And behold, a great red dragon
having seven heads and 10 horns and
seven crowns upon his heads.
Now that great red dragon represents
metaphorically Satan, the devil. Uh-huh.
Go ahead.
And his tail drew the third part of the
stars of heaven. And
the rest of the angels that that
followed him that that was deceived and
followed him. The other two/3s remain in
heaven. But the one-third of the angels
which are called the stars followed
Satan the devil and was cast out with
them. Did we finish that?
No. And did cast them to the earth. And
the dragon stood before the woman which
was ready to be delivered or to devour
her child as soon as it was born.
Thank you, brother. So therefore,
although it only mentions Satan, the
devil in Jude 1, it only mentions Satan
in uh uh Genesis the 3r chapter, only
Satan is mentioned. He is the tree of
the knowledge of good and evil or the
serpent. But the rest of the angel was
cast out into the earth with him. But
they had not been reserved upon the
chains of darkness. That's why the woman
could see him. He appeared to her in a
form but she talked she actually talked
to the devil. You know only after they
was uh only after he did his acts of
deception then the Lord put him and the
rest of the angels up under chains of
darkness. But they were there also. They
was already cast to the earth with him.
But that happened. They had not been uh
uh punished yet in the sense of uh so
the Lord fixed them that you can't see
them. That darkness represents something
that you cannot see. I hope that helped.
I hope the answer was understandable.
So Satan was in the garden,
but the rest of the angels were in the
earth also. It just mentioned him in
Genesis chapter 3 because he's the
chief.
All right. And we know that that that
Jude 6 uh James just read that right
quick since that was
big question and brother Julius add
something to it if need be. Go ahead
brother.
And the angels which kept not their
first estate but left their own
habitation. He has reserved in
everlasting chains under darkness until
the judgment of the great day.
He just fixed them so that you cannot
see them. So the but that happened after
they committed the trespass of deception
of uh Eve and Adam. So therefore uh it's
not that they didn't keep their first
step. They got cast out. That's why we
read Revelation 12. So he got them
reserved. You cannot see an evil angel.
I'm going to say it again. You cannot
see an evil angel but you see them
operating in people. That's why you say
he or she has an evil spirit because
they are being persuaded by that evil
spirit.
Yep. All right. Thank you for that,
brother. Hope that answered that
question. Uh guest caller, you with us?
Can you hear me?
Yes, sir.
Yeah. You with us now?
Yeah. Uhhuh.
Okay. We're going back to that Zechariah
uh the fifth chapter that you want to
pick up at verse 5.
Okay.
Okay. Zechariah 5:5 says, "Then the
angel that talked with me went forth and
said unto me, Lift up now thine eyes and
see what is this that goeth forth." And
I said, "What is it?" And he said, "This
is an Epha that goeth forth." He said,
"Moreover, this is their resemblance
through all the earth." And behold,
there was lifted up a talon of lead, and
this is a woman that siteth in the midst
of the epha. And he said, "This is
wickedness." And he cast it into the
midst of the epha, and he cast the
weight of lead upon the mouth thereof.
Then lifted I up my
Now this epha it's talking about is the
Catholic rosary. They have these beads.
Each one of these beads represents a
prayer
and and and the middle of that epo is is
the uh uh uh image of a woman. They call
it Mary.
But the whole thing is it goes back to
Simos Nimrod's
uh uh uh wife which is which is the uh
uh which the mother goddess. So we
talking about a Catholic rosary here.
Now go ahead and read.
Then lifted up lifted I up mine eyes and
look and behold there came out two women
and the wind was in their wings for they
had wings like the wings of a stor. And
they lifted up the eph between the earth
and the heaven. Then said I to the angel
that talked with me, whether do these
bear the epha. And he said unto me to
build an house in the land of Shinar,
and it shall be established and set
there upon her own base.
Now to show you that this is talking
about the Catholic Church and those uh
women with with wings uh uh
one of the Catholic symbolism that let
Zachariah letting us know that it's
going to happen in the future. Now we
can read this out of a book that's
called Babylon mystery religion. Now I'm
gonna ask you now I'm I'm gonna ask
brother Julius to read this because he
have my book the book that you that I'm
talking about and you can order it
yourself. So why don't you read that
junior to show you that this is talking
about the Catholic church because when
it go back to uh because Babylon Babel
and and that's where the Catholic church
is and it's set on its own foundation.
Did you finish that? Yes, I did.
So, that means that this is not on the
foundation of God. It's on his own
foundation. Now, why don't you read that
out of this mystery uh uh Babylon
mystery religion period?
This book is entitled Babylon Mystery
Religion, ancient and modern,
page 27. Closely connected with the idea
of praying to Mary is an instrument
called the rosary. It consists of a
chain with 15 sets of small beads. Each
set marked off by one large bead. The
ends of this chain are joined by a metal
bearing the imprint of Mary. From this
hangs a short chain at the end of which
of which is a crucifix. The beads on the
rosary are for counting prayers. Prayers
that are repeated over and over. Though
this instrument is widely used within
the Roman Catholic Church, it is clearly
not of Christian origin. It has been
known in many countries. The Catholic
Encyclopedia says, "In almost all
countries, then we meet with something
in the nature of prayer counters or
rosary beads." It goes on to site a
number of examples including a sculpture
of ancient Nineveh mentioned by Leert of
two winged females praying before a
sacred tree easy each beholding each
holding a rosary. So that's what this is
all about. The two women uh in this in
this Zachchariah represents this mystery
religion. And of course, here is the an
image of the rosary and right here at
the end of it is a cross with Mary on
it. So, but all that they call it a but
it's really representing the uh the
rosary with the image of Mary on it and
it all about timas and tamuz mother the
mother mother goddess and child worship.
That's what this is all about. pagan to
the core.
And and so it was established, you know,
in in the land of Shana, which is
Babylon. Okay?
And uh uh and this church. Now, let's go
into Revelation 17th chapter, and we
going to show you what this church is
that the uh built on its foundation that
these women with wings flew to and and
and with the rosaries and put took the
rosaries there. Revelation 17. And we're
going to start reading at verse one.
Okay.
We're going to read down to
We're going to read down to five.
Huh?
Okay. Revelation 17 and1 says, "And
there came one of the seven angels which
had the seven vows and talked with me,
saying unto me, come hither. I will show
unto thee the judgment of the great
[__] that siteth upon many waters, with
whom the kings of the earth committed
fornication, and the inhabitants of the
earth have been made drunk with the wine
of her fornication. So he carried So he
carried me away in the spirit into the
wilderness. And I saw a woman sit upon a
scarlet colored beast full of names and
blasphemy having seven heads and 10
horns. And the woman was arrayed in
purple and scarlet color and decked with
gold and precious stones and pearls
having a golden cup in her hand full of
abominations and filthiness of her
fornication. And upon her forehead was a
name written, mystery, Babylon the
great, the mother of harlots and
abominations of the earth.
So now this is what these two women with
wings like a stor was carrying. They was
carrying this epoar which is a rosary
and they set it up in China which
represent Babylon and which al and it
said is built on its own foundation
which represent Babylon the great the
castle religion
the mother of harlot that mean that all
these other little religions come out of
her but that's all that represent is the
make it short the Catholic church And
Zachchariah was just warned us warning
us about it because he knew that uh they
would they had this they would have this
stuff uh uh written and so you get this
book mystery Babylon
religion and you can find that in it.
That's all I have to say.
Babylon mystery religion ancient and mo
ancient and modern. And you need to get
a copy. go to Amazon or your local
library and see if you can find a copy
of this and it it it's got some deep
stuff in it. Thank you.
Also, I want to say that you can
download the PDF on your computer. All
you have to do is Google it and type in
Babylon Mystery Religion PDF and you can
download the whole book for free.
Okay. All right. Thank you brothers for
that information and we know that that
sheds some light on their question. As
we move on to our next one,
next one credit account says, "I want to
know if you are married and your wife is
on her monthly. Can you hug her or are
you supposed to be in a separate rooms
if you are living with each other?"
All right, brother Dre. What you say?
Let's go to Leviticus 15 and we going to
read verses 19 to 22.
Okay. Leviticus 15
19- 22 says, "And if a woman have an
issue, and her issue in her flesh be
blood, she shall be put apart seven
days, and whosoever touches her shall be
unclean until the evening.
and everything that she lith upon in her
separation shall be unclean. Everything
also that she siteth upon shall be
unclean. And whosoever toucheth her bed
shall wash his clothes and bathe himself
in water and be unclean until the
evening. And whosoever toucheth anything
that she set upon shall wash his clothes
and bathe himself in water and be
unclean until the evening.
So this this don't just apply to your
wife. You you open the door, you sit in
the chair when you go to a bus station,
you you go anywhere where a woman has
been sitting, you be unclean until the
evening and you need to wash yourself.
But to answer the question, this is what
the book is saying. Until the evening,
if you do that, but you ought to wash
yourself and you know, but can you touch
your wife? Of course you can. But you be
unclean until the evening until that
time is over with. That's all I got.
That's it, Brother Dre. Right on the
money. Cuz if you stay in a studio, how
can you avoid her? You
can't, man. Well, you can't. So, thank
you for that, brother. Hope that
answered their question. As we move on
to our next
next one, little mama Hayes asks,
"In Matthew 14 22-33,
Jesus walking on water. Was he in spirit
body?" Because they didn't recognize him
at first.
Well, no. He was in flesh and blood body
just like he was after Mary had um had
him since he was a little child. But he
was in flesh and blood. But when he came
in walking, it was unknown for a man
being able to walk on water. So they
didn't expect for it to be him being
that he is the carpenter's son. So but
let's go and read that. Matthew 14.
Okay. Matthew 14:es 22 and 23 says, "And
straightway Jesus constrained his
disciples to get into a ship and to go
before him unto the other side while he
sent the multitudes away." And when he
had sent the multitudes away, he went up
into a mountain apart to pray. And when
the e evening was come, he was there
alone. Mhm.
But the sh But the ship was not in the
midst of this now in the midst of the
sea, tossed with waves, for the wind was
contrary.
So the wind was very strong and the
waves too. Go ahead.
And in the fourth watch of the night,
Jesus went unto them walking on the sea.
And when the disciple
Mhm.
Oh yeah.
And when the disciples saw him walking
on the sea, they were troubled, saying,
"It is a spirit." And they cried out for
fear.
So they were in fear when they saw um
this man walking at 3:00 a.m. in the
morning on the water coming out to the
ship where they were at. And they were
afraid. So that's why they had assumed
it was a spirit. They didn't think it
was Jesus. But what happened? But
straightway Jesus spake unto them,
saying, Be of good cheer, it is I, be
not afraid.
And Peter answered him, and said, Lord,
if it be thou, bid me come unto thee on
the water.
And Peter was in flesh and blood, just
like Jesus was here. And so, let's see
what happened with Peter. Go ahead.
And he said, "Come." And when Peter was
come down out of the ship, he walked on
the water to go to Jesus.
Mhm.
But when he saw the wind boisterous, he
was afraid and beginning to sink, he
cried, saying, Lord, save me. And
immediately Jesus stretched forth his
hand, and caught him, and said unto him,
Oh thou of little faith, wherefore
didest thou doubt?
Yep, cuz he started to sink once he
started to doubt. Go ahead.
And when they were come into the ship,
the wind ceased. Then they were in the
ship came and worshiped him, saying, "Of
a truth, thou art the son of God."
So he was flesh and blood, just like
Peter walked out there on the water,
flesh and blood, too. Because Jesus was
the son of God, and he was just
exercising some of his power, walking on
water, and it was unheard of. And that's
why they were afraid. And that's all I
got. Anybody else?
All right, we're gonna leave it right
there. We hope that answered your
question, Sister Deborah. Next question
with the time check.
Yes, the time is uh 8:02.
Credit Account says, "If you pick up
coins on the street, is that considered
breaking the commandments of thou shalt
not steal?"
Right, brother Dre. Who them coins
belong to?
Right. Exactly. Who do the coins belong
to? If you if you are standing by
somebody paying for something in line
and they drop some coins out of their
pocket and you put your foot on the coin
until they walk away, yeah, you
But if you walk up on some coins and
find them and nobody is there, how could
that be stealing?
That's not stealing. So, you know, but
if you if you know whose stuff it is,
you return it. Let's go to uh Exodus 23.
We just going to read verse 4. Exodus 23
and verse 4.
Okay. Exodus 23:4
says,
"If thou meet thine enemy's ox or his
ass going astray, thou shall surely
bring it back to him again."
You don't take it into your house
because in into your your uh stock and
make it yours when you see it going
astray, you bring it back to them. The
same way with money. You know, if
somebody drop a coin or something and
hey man, you dropped that. You know,
you get it.
That's all that's all I got on that.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we move on to our next question,
moving on. Most love asks for you to
explain Psalms 34 verse 18.
Psalms 34 and 18. Let's go there.
dealing with that broken heart, brother
James, and contrite spirit, which is um
let's read it first. Go ahead.
Okay. Psalm 34:18 says, "The Lord is
nigh unto them that are of a broken
heart, and savor such as be of a
contrite spirit."
So Lord is nigh unto them that are of a
broken heart, and such and such as of a
contrite spirit. So, if you're sorrowful
and repentful, hey, the Lord be with
you. And let's go into um Psalms 14.
Turn back to Psalms 14.
And let's pick it up.
I'm sorry. Psalm 147. Psalm 147:3.
Psalm 147 and3.
Okay. Psalm 147 and3 says, "He health
healeth the broken in heart and bindeth
up their wounds."
Yeah. So it's the Lord that health the
broken in heart because Lord know we
need him all day every day. Now turn
over to Matthew 5. Matthew 5. And let's
let's pick it up at that verse three
because these are some of the sorrowful
and and humble hearts and contrite
spirit. Let's go ahead and read some of
that. Go ahead.
Okay.
Blessed are the poor in spirit, for
theirs is the kingdom of heaven.
Yes, you can even be repentful in that.
Go ahead.
Blessed are they that mourn, for they
shall be comforted.
It's sorrowful. Go ahead.
Blessed are the meek, for they shall
inherit the earth.
Blessed Blessed are they which do hunger
and thirst after righteousness, for they
shall be filled. Yeah. Sometime you can
be of a broken heart and you looking for
that righteousness. Hey, and the Lord
will make sure you find it when you seek
it with all your heart. Go ahead.
Blessed are the merciful, for they shall
obtain mercy. Blessed are the pure in
heart, for they shall see God. Blessed
are the peacemakers, for they shall be
called the children of God.
And you can read the rest of that. would
also put you on line with that repentive
and humble spirit and contritess. And
that's all I got on that. Anybody else?
All right, we're going to leave it right
there as we move on to our next
question.
Next question. ity as in Matthew 5:18
and Matthew 24:34
it says that this generation shall not
pass from the law till it be fulfilled.
When will the law be fulfilled?
Yeah, it will not pass until it's
fulfilled. Let's go to that Matthew 5.
Matthew 5 and pick it up at that 18
brother and the guest caller will take
it from that. Okay. Matthew 5:18 says,
"For verily I say unto you, till heaven
and earth pass, one jot or one tit shall
in no wise pass from the law till all be
fulfilled.
Guess caller, you with us?"
Okay. Now, can you hear me now?
Yes, sir.
Okay. The law of evil was was talking
about fulfilled that which was written
about him.
Okay. You know, and and it was fulfilled
when Jesus died and rose again because
it was uh uh uh uh it because it was
talking about him. Now, let's go and
look at it. Let's go into Luke 24th
chapter
and uh uh
let's pick it up
at verse 25
because Jesus rose from the dead and
these people didn't know and even
disciples didn't know that he was
supposed to rise from the dead. So these
guys was talking about you know we
thought he was the one you know and
Jesus uh came and started talking with
them and he he disguised himself and
they didn't know who he was. So now
first thing is
he told them he called them fools. Okay
let's let's start at 24 and uh uh uh
Luke 24 and start reading at verse 25.
Go ahead.
Okay. Luke 24:2
says, "Then he said unto them, oh fools
and slow of heart to believe all that
the prophets have spoken. Ought not
Christ to have suffered these things,
and to enter into his glory?"
And beginning at Moses and all the
prophets, he expounded unto them in all
the scriptures the things concerning
himself.
So this is these are the the uh uh this
is these are this is the prophecy that
all of it had to be fulfilled
then heaven and earth would pass away
but not uh but uh uh uh will not you
know before this prophecy would fall
down. So he he called them fools to
believe all that the prophets said
concerning him and he started at Moses
and he actually ran all the books down
to himself. Now skip down to verse 44
and read from 44 to 46.
Go ahead.
Verse 44. It says, "And he said unto
them, these are the words which I spake
unto you while I was yet with you that
all things must be fulfilled which were
written in the law of Moses and in the
prophets and in the Psalms concerning
me."
Then un then opened he their
understanding that they might understand
the scriptures and said unto them thus
it is written and thus it behooved
Christ to suffer and to rise from the
dead the third day.
Now he was talking. So when he said that
prophecies he come not to uh uh change
the law the prophets but to fulfill he
came to fulfill his part and everything
that was written about him starting in
Moses and went through the Psalms and
all the other prophecy. Jesus fulfilled
all of it. Goes like in uh 122nd chapter
of Psalms and said the uh my God, my
God, why have thee why have thou
forsaken me? Then he have in that same
122nd chapter he said they nailed my
they they uh uh uh pierced my hands and
my feet.
Yeah.
Then you got in another it says that uh
uh that uh they gave him vinegar to
drink. Now before he even died he said I
thirst. And once he and then when they
what they did they got some vinegar on a
sponge and put it up to his mouth. Once
he t the vine he said it is finished.
then he died. So a prophecy that he's
talking about is talking about what was
written about him. That's what he came
to fulfill.
Not all prophecy because a lot of
prophecy uh uh uh include us. But what
statement there in Matthews 5 and 18
that prophecy is a prophecy talking
about him and he and he fulfilled every
bit of it.
Now let's go to the next one.
Matthews 24 and 34.
Okay. Matthew 24 and 34.
Now that's the end that one 5 and 18.
Let you know that the prophet he was
talking about was prophesied by him.
That's what he fulfilled. Now we going
to the second part of this.
Okay. Matthew 24:34
says, "Verily I say unto you, this
generation shall not pass till all
things be fulfilled."
Now, that's talking about the generation
that see these signs that was mentioned
in Matthew the 24th chapter because the
apostles came because he he they was
talking about how beautiful the temple
was. Then uh Jesus told him said look
they going to come and there's not going
to be one stone left upon another on
this temple. It's going to be torn down.
Then they ask him then when will this
take when will this be and when will you
when will you when will it will you come
and when will it when will the end and
what will be the end of the world?
So they asking some specific question.
So he told them what it was. He told
them about the abomination stand in the
holy place. He said when you see that
flea and he told them a whole lot of
other things. But then he told them also
that uh uh the generation that see these
not talking about that particular
generation in his time. He's saying the
generation in the future when they see
all these signs that's written about in
Matthew the 24th chapter. That
generation will not pass until all of it
come to pass.
Not the generation in his time and most
likely the generation in our time. We
will see the end of this cuz already
they talking about the red heer and
building the temple.
Yeah.
They build that temple
and papa move from Rome move into it.
Then the abomination of desolation will
be standing the holy place. Then once
that happened, the Lord told us to flee
to the wilderness because there going to
be great tribulation such as there had
never been before. Then it goes on to
tell you about Jesus coming. And it
tells you about he set his hand a second
time to recover the house of Israel.
Going to send his angels and recover
Israel. He so the generation see all
these stuff
that he spoke about in 24th chapter of
St. Matthews, that generation will see
the coming of the Lord. That's all I
have to say.
That's right. And that's why the Lord
say, "Who so reader, let him
understand."
Correct.
Yep. All right. We hope that answered
your question as we move on to our next
one.
Moving on. Bonnie Henderson asks in
Isaiah 56:es
1 and 2 and 6 through8,
"Why is the Lord merciful to people
today for not keeping the Sabbath day?
Is it because the Sunday law is not
enforced yet?"
Adre, what' you say about that Isaiah
56?
Let's go. Let's go read that. Let's go
read Isaiah 56 1 and 2 and then we'll
skip down to 6 and 8. Go ahead, brother.
When you get
Isaiah 56 1 verse 1 and two says, "Thus
sayeth the Lord, keep your judgment and
do justice for my salvation is near to
come and my righteousness to be
revealed.
Blessed is the man that doeth this, and
the son of man that layeth hold on it,
that keepeth the Sabbath from polluting
it, and keeping his hand from doing any
evil.
So, he's saying here that blessed is the
man that doeth it. Now, you may be
asking the question about, well, what
about the people that's not keeping it
today? Because right here he's talking
about blessed is the man that doeth it
and that keepeth the Sabbath from
polluting. Skip down to verse 6 and 8.
Go ahead.
And the sons of the stranger that join
themselves to the Lord to serve him and
to love the name of the Lord to be his
servants. Everyone that keepeth the
Sabbath from polluting it, and taketh
hold of my covenant, even them will I
bring to my holy mountain, and make them
joyful in my house of prayer. Their
burnt offerings and their sacrifices
shall be accepted upon mine altar. For
mine house shall be called an house of
prayer for all people.
Go ahead. The L the Lord God which
gathered the outcast of Israel saith,
yet will I gather others to him beside
those that are gathered unto him.
So we see here that the Sabbath was made
for man. It's not just for Israel. It
says blessed is the man and it deals
with the stranger as well. Now, as
pertaining to those that seem to be
blessed right now that's doing Sunday,
let's look at something else. Let's go
to second Peter the third chapter.
Second Peter the 3 chapter.
Second Peter 3 and we going to pick it
up at verse
8.
No, no, bag up. back up and read uh
verse
well verse
verse three started
okay
go ahead
second Peter 3
chap verse three says knowing this first
that there shall come in the last days
scoffers walking after their own lust
and saying where is the promise of his
coming for since the fathers fell asleep
sleep. All things continue as they were
from the beginning of the creation.
For this
think that the Lord why you know the
Lord is is just patient with people and
he is but this is why these things are
skip down to verse N and read that. The
Lord is not slack concerning his
promise, as some men count slackness,
but is long-suffering to usward, not
willing that any should perish, but that
all should come to repentance.
See, and that's the thing. The Lord
wants us to come to repentance.
He don't want you to not keep the
Sabbath. He wants He's long-suffering to
us, Lord. And he don't want none to
perish. And he's sending warers to warn
people. But if they don't take heed,
they don't take heed. That is their
choice. But the word is being taught.
The Lord is long-suffering. He's not
willing that any should perish, but that
all come to repentance.
So I hope that that answers your
question. That's all I got.
You muted, Cornell.
Yes, sir. Dre, thank you. They say, "Why
is he merciful?" He sit on the mercy
seat, too, don't he?
Yes, he does, brother.
Yes. And we are thankful. All right,
we're gonna move on to our next
question.
Next question. Detroit. Troy Price asks
in 1 Corinians 6 verse 19 when it says
your body is the temple of the Holy
Ghost. Who does the term Holy Ghost
refer to?
All right, Jerome,
it it's referring to his word. His word
is holy in his spirit. And that's what
he want dwell in you said. He said, "Let
his word dwell in you richly." All
right, but let's go to uh St. John
chapter 6. But before then, let's read
the verse that they gave. I think it was
1 Corinthians 6 and 19. And then we'll
go to St. John 6 after that. Okay.
Okay. 1 Corinthians 6:19 says, "What
know ye not? Your body is the temple of
the Holy Ghost which is in you which ye
have of God and ye are not your own.
Yeah. He want that word dwelling in your
temple.
Okay. That's your body. Okay.
And he want it dwelling in your mind.
That's why he want his word dwelling in
there richly. All right. So now let's go
and see this referred to as spirit.
Let's go to St. John 6 verse 63.
Okay. St. John 6 verse 63 says,
"It is the spirit that quickenth. The
flesh profitth nothing. The words that I
speak unto you, they are spirit and they
are life."
Yeah. So that's the spirit he want
dwelling in you in your temple, which is
your body, in your brain. Okay? And
it'll lead you into eternal life. Let's
go to Romans the 8th chapter.
And we going to read verse 11. Then we
going to skip.
Romans 8 11 says, "But if the spirit of
him that raised up Jesus from the dead
dwell in you, he that raised up Christ
from the dead shall also quicken your
mortal bodies by his spirit that
dwelleth in you."
Yeah. And that spirit is his word. Verse
13 and 14.
For if ye live after the flesh, ye shall
die. But if ye through the spirit do
mortify the deeds of the body, ye shall
live. For as many as are led by the
spirit of God, they are the sons of God.
Yep. Led by his word, the words of
eternal life. That's all I got on you.
Yes, sir. Put on that spirit of God. All
right, we're going to move on to our
next question.
Next question. Melon Natural Journey
asks, "Are prayer candles considered
witchcraft?"
Prayer candles. What you say, Brother
Julius?
Prayer candles are used in witchcraft.
They're also used in pagan worship.
They're also used in homebuilt shrines
or homebuilt altars. It is not biblical.
Let me show you what is biblical. Let's
go to St. John 4.
And metaphorically speaking, we can read
the word candlesticks, but that
represents and and depend upon the
context them angels like in Revelation
the first chapter. But it is not
biblical.
St. John 4, brother James, read verse
24.
Okay? says, "God is a spirit, and they
that worship him must worship him in
spirit and in truth."
Not with prayer candles.
Not with prayer candles. You must
worship God in spirit and in truth. If
he wanted you to use prayer cles
candles, it would have been written. And
the motto of the Israel of God is if you
cannot read it, then don't believe it.
So it is a pagan practice practiced by
many ancient cultures especially in the
Catholic church. It is not biblical. So
if it's not biblical but it is used in
witchcraft and uh wic seances and so on
has nothing to do with the God of
Israel. That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that brother.
As we move on to our next one.
Next one. Cool Blue asks, "Is there a
specific way to pray or are there any
occasions where we have to pray
differently?"
All right, brother Julius, help cool
blue.
The definition of prayer is a solemn
request for help or giving. We going to
call him the God of Israel thanks
because there ain't no other God beside
him. So therefore
uh the Lord told you how to pray in
Matthew the 6th chapter. You pray the
Lord can hear you anywhere. However,
when a woman is praying, her head is to
be covered. When a man is praying, his
head is to be uncovered. That is first
Corinthians the 11th chapter. So those
are the ways that we pray. Now what we
do in the Israel of God, we face the
east. We could read that in 2 Chronicles
uh uh the seventh chapter. Let's go
there and read that
two verses. 2 Chronicles 7:15- 16 and
that'll be it. 2 Chronicles
chapter 7
and read verse
[Music]
uh pick up at 14.
Okay.
2 Chronicles 74-16
says, "If my people which are called by
my name shall humble themselves and pray
and seek my face and turn from their
wicked ways, then will I hear from
heaven and will forgive their sin and
will heal their land."
Continue.
Now mine eyes shall be open and my ears
attent unto the prayer that is made in
this place.
Uhhuh. For now have I chosen and
sanctified this house that my name may
be there forever and my eyes and my
heart shall be there perpetually.
And that was when the temple was there
in the land of Jerusalem. But we're not
praying to a temple. We're praying to
where the temple stood. The Lord can
hear you anywhere. But what we do is we
try to be obedient to the word of God.
So us being here in Chicago, we face the
east.
If you're over in the eastern
hemisphere, you might face the as east
of Jerusalem, you might face the west.
But that's all I got. I hope that
helped.
Yeah, helps too, Julius, is to pray. And
when you pray, believe that you shall
receive, too.
That's what James said. Uh uh when you
pray, believe in what you're asking for.
That's right. Yes, sir.
Be right.
That's that's also in first kings 8 19
and 20 and uh 29 and 30 as well.
Okay. All right. Thank you all for that.
Let's move on to our next question
sister.
Yes. Next question. MJ asks, "What is
meant by I will take you one of a city
and two of a family in Jeremiah 3:14."
One of a city and two of a family in
Jeremiah 3 and 14. Let's go there,
brother James.
3 and 14. And I guess the caller would
take it from there.
Okay. Jeremiah 3:14 says, "Turn, O
backsliding children, sayeth the Lord,
for I am married unto you, and I will
take you one of a city and two of a
family, and I will bring you to Zion."
That's uh that's only talking about the
return of Israel. That's right. Return
to backsliding children.
That's that's when he's talking about
when he's going to come and he's going
to return and gather Israel from the
four winds of heaven. That's reading
from from all over the earth. Let's look
at Deuteronomy the 30th chapter
and we're going to read verses 1-4.
Okay. Deuteronomy 30th chapter verses
1-4 says, "And it shall come to pass
when all these things are come upon
thee, the blessing and the curse, which
I have set before thee, and thou shalt
call them to mine among all the nations,
whether the Lord thy God has driven
thee, and shalt return unto the Lord thy
God, and shalt obey his voice, according
to all that I command thee this day,
thou and thy children with all thine
heart, and with all thy soul, that then
the Lord thy God will turn thy
captivity, and have compassion upon
thee, and will return and gather thee
from all the nations, whether the Lord
thy God has scattered thee. If any of
thine be driven out unto the outermost
parts of heaven, from thence will the
Lord thy God gather thee, from thence he
will fetch thee.
Okay, he's letting you know that no
matter where you are going to gather you
whether it's as a family or whether it's
an individual, he's not going to leave
one Israelite scattered in the old in
the other nation just like he didn't
leave one Israelite down in Egypt. Let's
go to one more place. Matthew's 24th
chapter and we're going to read verse
27.
Then we're going to skip down to 29
and read to 31.
Okay, that was Matthew the 24th chapter
starting with what verse again?
Verse 27 first, then we're going to see.
Okay. Okay. Verse 27 says, "For as the
lightning cometh out of the east, and
shineth even unto the west, so shall
also the coming of the Son of Man be."
Uh-huh. Skip down to verse 29 and
continue.
Immediately after the tribulation of
those days shall the sun be darkened,
and the moon shall not give her light,
and the stars shall fall from heaven,
and the powers of heaven of the heavens
shall be shaken. And then shall appear
the sign of the Son of Man in heaven.
And then shall all the tribes of the
earth mourn, and they shall see the Son
of Man coming in the clouds of heaven
with power and great glory.
And he shall send his angels with a
great sound of a trumpet and they shall
gather together his elect from the four
winds from one end of heaven to the
other.
So that's what it said in Deuteronomy.
The Lord going to return and he going to
gather all Israel
whether it's one or whether it's a
family or whether it's a crowd. You're
not going to leave one and they going to
take You finished that, right?
Yes. That finished at 31.
Uhhuh. And he's going to take us all
back to the land of Israel. No matter
where we are, even if we don't know who
we are, Isaiah said they going to grab
you. Even the strangers going to grab
you and bring you back. So that's all
that's saying
that he's going to return recover Israel
and take us all back to the land. That's
all I have to say.
All right. I hope that answered your
question, Sister Deborah. Time check for
our next.
Yes, the time is 8:32.
Ran 64 says, "Is there only one
description of the angel other than them
having four heads and six wings? Do some
look like a normal man?"
All right, Brother Jerome.
Uh,
I'm gonna answer that question in two
parts. Um let's look at the Daniel's 10
to give you a description
uh of an angel where it don't say four
faces or six wings but it gives him this
description of an angel. Okay. Uh go to
Daniel's the 10th chapter. Okay.
And read verse 4-6.
Okay. Daniel 10:es 4-6 says, "And in the
fourth and or in the four and 20th day
of the first month, as I was by the side
of the great river, which is Hidecio,
then I lifted up mine eyes and looked,
and behold, a certain man clothed in
linen, whose loins were girded with fine
gold of
his body was also also was like the
burl, and his face as the appearance
appearance of lightning, and his eyes as
lamps of fire, and his arms and his feet
like in color to polish brass, and the
voice of his words like the voice of a
multitude.
Okay. Now, I don't know if all of the
angels
uh that God created got four faces and
six wings. Okay. Um, but in dealing with
it from another direction, whatever they
look like, if they happen to appear to
you, and we talking about the ones that
can be seen, cuz like it was established
earlier, none of the wicked angels can
be seen. But if the holy angels appear
to you and they happen to look like a
man, let's go to that uh Hebrews the
13th chapter and read that verse two.
You could be uh entertaining angels and
not be aware of it.
Okay?
So let's go to the Hebrews chapter 13
and verse two.
It says, "Be not forgetful to entertain
strangers, for thereby some have
entertained angels unawares."
Yeah. So they can come to you looking
like a man,
you know, even though they really
angels. Okay, that's all I got in. If
anybody want to add something.
Yeah, I want to throw in something. The
ones that have the full face
are called cherub angels.
They are different from others. Those
are the ones that Lord put around him in
the garden of Eden. They're called
cherub angels. Okay. Those are the ones
that have for none of the rest of them
have it.
That's all I have to say.
All right. Hope that answered your
question.
Yep. Chair BMS. Okay.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Yes, we are now into tonight's Q&A for
Wednesday, July the 9th, 2025.
Marcus Kimbro asks, "Are we supposed to
not eat the little pieces of fat that is
left on a cooked well done piece of
steak? Just trying to get clarification
on not eating the fat of animals.
All right, brother Jerome, when you see
that fat on the edge, share some light.
Well, um I see that you familiar that
the Lord don't want us to eat the fat.
So, I won't go to that verse on that.
But understand the Lord, he lookth on
the heart. He want you to remove as much
of that fat as you possibly can remove.
Okay? And then he looking at your heart.
He's saying it ain't your intentions to
eat the fat and you removing the fat as
much as fat as you possibly can remove.
Okay? Do that. And I I believe the Lord
will be okay with you. You know, uh,
anybody want to add something, they can.
Yep. Film the fact. Period.
Yeah.
Y.
All right, hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Next one. Z Israel asks in Proverbs 6
verse 19, can you explain and give us an
example of what sowing discord among the
brethren means?
All right, brother Dre.
Yeah. Let's go to that Proverbs 6 and we
are going to pick it up at 16 because it
gives the examples
of discord.
Yes sir.
Go ahead.
Proverbs Proverbs 6 and verse 16 says,
"These six things doeth the Lord hate.
Yay. Seven are an abomination unto him.
A proud look, a lying tongue, and hands
that shed innocent blood, and heart that
deviseth wicked imaginations, feet that
be swift in running to mischief, a false
witness that speaketh lies, and he that
sweth discord among brethren.
Yeah, discord is strife, division,
disagreement, and lack of harmony.
That's what discord is. and and a proud
look, a lying tongue, hands that shed
innocent blood, a heart that devisth
wicked imaginations,
feet running the mischief, a false
witness that speaketh lies, all of them
things.
So discord,
you know, when you ban false witness on
a person, are you a tailbearer?
that souls discord. Now, let's look at
something that's the total opposite of
this that God wants us to do. Let's go
to Zechariah
8 and we going to read verses 16 and 17.
Zechariah 8 16 and 17.
Okay. Zechariah 8 16 and 17 says, "These
are the things that ye shall do. Speak
ye every man the truth to his neighbor.
Execute the judgment of truth, and peace
in your gates,
and let none of you imagine evil in your
hearts against his neighbor, and love no
false oath. For all these are things
that I hate, sayeth the Lord. So those
are those are the things that we should
do and the things that we shouldn't do
because all of those things that's
mentioned those seven things the Lord
hate they so discord. So I hope that
helps.
All right thank you for that brother as
we move on to our next question.
Next one. Brother Anthony Horsey says,
"I had a brother ask me who was the
father of Joseph, the husband of Mary."
He said in Matthew 1 verse 16, it says
Jacob, but in Luke 3 23 it says Hei is
the father of Joseph. Which one is
correct, Matthew or Luke?
All right, let's go to Matthew 1
and verse 16 because he's asking about
uh who is the father of Joseph. Matthew
1 and 16. And when you get there, the
guest caller take it from there.
Okay. Matthew 1:16 says, "And Jacob
begat Joseph, the husband of Mary, of
whom was born Jesus, who is called
Christ."
Go to the next one.
Okay. And then Luke Luke uh 3 and
3 and 23 says
Oh, hold on. Is that correct? Three.
Yes.
Okay. It says, "And Jesus himself be to
be about 30 years of age, being as was
supposed the son of Joseph, which was
the son of Heli.
True for the matter is
I don't know.
All I know is that Jesus when he was
born, it was not coming from flesh and
blood. The body was prepared for him.
For who Joseph father was, which one of
these guys, I don't have no clear
biblical uh uh direction that I can
point you in. Therefore, I have to say I
don't know.
All right, and we'll leave it right
there as we move on to our next
question.
Next one. Terron Blanc says, "Can you
explain Matthew 24 20 through 22?" I
understand the winter, but why not the
Sabbath?
All right, Brother Julius, they say they
understand why not the winter, but they
don't understand the Sabbath.
Let's go to the scripture, James, and
read it. Okay. Matthew 24 20-22 say,
"But pray ye that your flight be not in
winter, neither on the Sabbath day, for
then shall be great tribulation, such as
was not since the beginning of the world
to this time, no, nor ever shall be."
And except And except those days be
shortened, there should no flesh be
saved. But for the elect's sake, those
days shall be shortened.
Now, let's go to Mark the 13th chapter
and look at it from another point of
view. Mark chapter 13.
Okay, Mark chapter 13.
And we going to read verses. We're going
to read verses 19 and 20.
Okay, that says, "For in those days,"
pick it up at 14.
Okay, verse 14. But when ye shall see
the abomination of desolation spoken of
by Daniel the prophet standing where it
ought not, let him that readeth
understand. Then let them that be in
Judea flee to the mountains.
Skip down to verse 19.
For in those days shall be affliction,
such as was not from the beginning of
the creation, which God created until
this time, neither shall be. and accept.
Now, now it come
in Matthew. It uh it mimics uh Matthew
the 24th chapter.
The great tribulation is Satan's wrath
upon the servant, the true servants of
God. That's why it's going to be great
tribulation. Not uh because if you got
that mark, if you if you if you don't
take the mark of the beast, you could be
killed,
you know. Uh you can't buy or sell if
you don't have the mark of the beast.
It's going to be great tribulation. So
bad. There's never been a time like it
before, nor is it shall be. So in the
winter time, we know in the Sabbath
everything is shut down. But because but
the bottom line is this is a worldwide
assault on the true servants of God
orchestrated by Satan, devil, and
carried out by the beast and false
prophet. So therefore uh this is great
persecution against the commandment
keepers
and the the Sabbath day identifies the
commandment keepers. Let's go to Exodus.
This is my last place. Exodus 31.
Okay.
Exodus chapter 31
and we going to read verse I want to say
13.
Okay.
Exodus 31.
Okay. and 13 because the Sabbath day is
a sign between the Lord and his saints.
Go ahead.
Would you like me to back up to 12?
Pick it up at verse 12.
And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
Speak thou also unto the children of
Israel, saying, Verily, my Sabbaths ye
shall keep. For it is a sign between me
and you throughout your generations,
that ye may know that I am the Lord that
doeth sanctify you.
Read it again at 17. That'll be it.
It is a sign between me and the children
of Israel forever. For in six days the
Lord made heaven and earth. And on the
seventh day he rested and was refreshed.
So this this great tribulation is going
to affect the whole world, but
especially the affliction and the
persecution against the Sabbathke
keepers and the commandment keepers of
God. That's all I got. If anybody want
to add.
Yeah, brother Julius. We also got a
lesson on that. The wilderness, the
place of safety during the great
tribulation
and that is where you want to flee. Uh
somebody told me, "Well, that's for the
people in that time." No, that is for
anybody that has understanding. You get
to the place of safety.
That's right. Yes, indeed. All right. We
hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one.
Next question. If someone knows how to
put herbs together for illnesses, is it
considered a gift of healing? Scripture,
please.
Well, we said no last week, and no still
stands this week. But let's go quickly
to Psalms 103, brother. Psalms 103.
Psalms 103.
And when you get there, pick it up in
that verse one for me. And let's see who
is it that does the healing here. Go
ahead.
Bless the Lord, oh my soul, and all that
is within me, bless his holy name. Mhm.
Bless the Lord, oh my soul, and forget
not all his benefits.
What else?
Who forgiveth all thine iniquities, who
health all thy diseases.
Oh, can heal them all, huh, Brother
Jane?
Yes, sir.
Come back to Deuteronomy 32. Deuteronomy
32 right quick.
Okay. And when you get there, I want you
to read that uh verse 39 for me. And
let's pick it up from another angle
here.
Okay? Deuteronomy 32:39
says, "See now that I, even I am he, and
there is no God with me. I kill and I
make alive. I wound and I heal. Neither
is there any that can deliver out of my
hand."
That's quite a resume there, ain't it,
brother?
Yes, sir.
All right, read 40.
For I lift up my hand to heaven and say,
I live forever.
One more place. Matthew 10. Matthew 10.
And let's see. Even when man is able to
heal you, where does he get his power
from? Matthew 10 and just one verse.
Verse one. Go ahead.
And when he had called unto him his 12
disciples,
called unto him his 12 disciples. Go
ahead.
He gave them power against unclean
spirits to cast them out and to heal all
manner of sickness and all manner of
disease.
That's a bad God that can heal it all,
can't he?
Yes indeed.
And that is to whom we give the glory
and honor to. That's all I got.
Let's move to our next question. Sister,
as time is a ticking because we are
having fun.
Moving on. TX Domino says, "If the Holy
Spirit is an angel,
can I get some clarification on first
Peter 1 verse 12?"
If the Holy Spirit is an angel and they
want some clarif clarification on which
first Peter 1 verse 12
1 verse 12. Why don't you read that and
then we'll ask the guest caller if he
could shed some light on that. First
Peter 1 and 12.
Okay. 1 Peter 1 and verse 12 says, "Unto
whom it was revealed that not unto
themselves, but unto us they did
minister the things which are now
reported unto you by them that have
preached the gospel unto you with the
Holy Ghost sent down from heaven, which
things the angels desire to look into."
First thing I'm saying is this guy had
heard one leg of a four leg
lesson
concerning the spirit of God in his many
forms. You should have waited till the
end. Then you wouldn't ask this
question. But since you asked, we'll
deal with it. Now we going to back up.
You see when he say uh uh unto whom it
was revealed, we going to find out who
it was that he was talking about.
Let's back up the ninth chapter or ninth
verse rather and read down to that.
Okay. Verse N says, "Receiving the end
of your faith, even the salvation of
your souls, of which salvation the
prophets have inquired and searched
diligently, who prophesied of the grace
that should come unto you." Searching
the prophets, the prophets that prophesy
of this grace that's going to come to
you. Isn't that correct?
Yes, sir. Go ahead.
searching what or what manner of time
the spirit of Christ which was in them
did signify when it testified beforehand
the sufferings of Christ and the glory
that should follow
now the spirit of Christ that was in
them isn't that what it correct
yes
go ahead
unto whom it was revealed that not unto
themselves but unto us they did minister
the things which are now reported unto
you by them that have preached the
gospel unto you with the Holy Ghost sent
down from heaven, which things the
angels desire to look into.
So the prophets, they uh uh uh
prophesied
with the Holy Ghost that was in them.
Isn't that what it said?
Right down.
Now let's go into second Peter the first
chapter and read verses 15- 21. Let me
make sure that we understand
who this uh uh uh uh Holy Ghost that was
sent down from heaven that was in him.
Okay. Second Peter 1:15 says, "Moreover,
I will endure that ye may be able after
my decree
to have these things always in
remembrance.
For we have not followed cunning,
devised fables, when we made known unto
you the power and coming of our Lord
Jesus Christ, but were eyewitnesses of
his majesty." Mhm.
For he received from God the Father
honor and glory when there came such a
voice to him from the excellent glory.
This is my beloved son in whom I am well
pleased.
And this voice and this voice which came
from heaven we heard when we were with
him in the holy mount. When we have also
a more sure word of prophecy where unto
we have more also a more sure word of
prophecy. Go ahead. where unto ye do
well that ye take heed as until light
that shineth in a dark place until the
day dawn and the day star arise in your
hearts. Knowing this first
Knowing this first that no prophecy of
the scripture is of any private
interpretation.
For the prophecy came not in old time by
the will of men, but holy men of God
spake as they were moved by the Holy
Ghost.
Okay? They was moved by the Holy Ghost.
This is talking about the word. Let me
show you now. Let's go in 17 chapter of
Psalm and read verse 17
to 20.
Okay. 1 10 the 107th Psalm vers
17- 20.
Okay, it says fools because of their
transgression and because of their
iniquities are afflicted. Their soul
uphoreth all manner of meat and they
draw near unto the gates of death. Then
they cry unto the Lord in their trouble,
and he saveth them out of their
distresses. He sent his
pardon me.
How did he do that? Read it.
He sent his word and healed them and
delivered them from their destructions.
Oh, he sent his word and that is what
healed them because if you walk in the
word of God, you will be healed. But
then let's show you what what how the
Lord spoke to Israel. Let's go into
Nehemiah 9.
We're going to read verse 21
and verse 26
and verse 30.
Okay. Okay.
Nehemiah 9 verse 21
says, "Yay, 40 years did thou sustain
them in the wilderness, so that they
lack nothing. Their clothes waxed not
old, and their feet swelled not."
Uh-huh.
Then you said 26,
right?
Okay. It says, "Nevertheless, they were
disobedient and rebelled against thee,
and cast thy law behind their backs, and
slew thy prophets, which testified
against them, to turn them to thee, and
they wrought great provocations."
Uhhuh.
Okay. And verse 30 says, "Yet many years
did thou forbear them and testified
against them by the spirit and thy
prophets, yet would they not give ear,
therefore gavest thou them into the hand
of the people of the lands."
He testified against them with his
spirit and his spirit and his prophet.
How did the prophet get that spirit? He
sent it down. That's his word.
Yeah. Just like Jesus last place, just
like Jesus told these told Israel. Let's
go to St. John the 6th chapter
and we're going to read the uh uh uh
verse 21
rather.
Okay.
John John 6 verse 51.
Uhhuh. Read it.
I am the living bread.
Mhm.
Which came down from heaven.
If any man eat of this bread, he shall
live forever. And the bread that I will
give is my flesh, which I will give thee
for the life of the world.
Go ahead.
The Jews therefore strove among
themselves, saying, How can this man
give us his flesh to eat? Then Jesus
said unto them, "Verily, verily, I say
unto you, except ye eat the flesh of the
Son of Man, and drink his blood, ye have
no life in you.
Whosoever eateth my flesh and drinkkeeth
my blood hath eternal life, and I will
raise him up at the last day."
Now, skip down to verse verse 60.
Okay?
Read it.
Many therefore of his disciples when
they heard this said, "This is an hard
saying. Who can hear it?" When Jesus
knew it himself that the disciples
murmured at it, he said unto them,
"Doeth this offend you?"
Now, do this offend you? Skip down to
verse 63 and read it.
It is the spirit that quickenth. The
flesh profitth nothing. The words that I
speak unto you, they are spirit and they
are life.
That's right.
Come on. So the Holy Ghost in them that
he spoke with was the word of God.
That's how you're going to get life.
That's what's going to be in you. 66 to
68. And that's it.
From that time many of his disciples
went back and walked no more with him.
Then said Jesus unto the twel, "Will ye
also go away?" Then Simon Peter answered
him,"Lord,
to whom shall we go? Thou hast the words
of eternal life."
Amen.
So now the whole thing is the Holy Ghost
that he uh uh uh uh that he sent down
from heaven was his word.
And when this word enter you, how does
it enter you? Somebody have to teach it
or you read it.
And that is sent down from heaven. The
word of God, it will heal you. It will
save you. It will get you eternal life.
Angel bring it. But what he bring is the
word of God. That's all I have to say.
That's
right. You got to walk in.
All right.
I suggest to the one that asked this
question,
get a whole series before you start
asking question. Who knows? You might be
educated.
That's
right. Stay tuned. There's more to come.
Much more.
Hey, is it all right if we read that
Revelation guest caller Revelations 1 to
back up what you were saying about the
holy angel gonna give you the holy word.
Do it.
Yeah. Revelations one
and one
and then one and two.
Okay. Revelation 1:es 1 and 2 says, "The
revelation of Jesus Christ, which God
gave unto him to show unto his servants
things which must shortly come to pass.
And he sent and signified it by his
angel unto his servant John, who bare
record of the word of God, and of the
testimony of Jesus Christ, and of all
things that he sought."
Amen.
All right.
Yep. Thank you for that ad on there,
brother. And Sister Deborah, time for
one more question before we bring this
to a close. Go right ahead.
Yeah. Uh Ni Jones uh says, "Can you
please explain how Esau is the white
man?"
Uh we never said that, but uh let's open
that. Not on this program. Let's open it
up to the panel.
Well, Esau is not the white man. We
going to go to white man first. Go to
Genesis the 10th chapter and read about
JFA and this seed.
Okay. Genesis 10 uh starting. Would you
like for me to start at verse one?
Yeah. Pick it up at one.
Okay.
Now these are the generations of the son
of Noah, Shim, Ham, and Japheth. And
unto them were sons born after the
flood. The sons of Japath, Gomar, and
Magog, and Maidi, and Jan, and Tubal,
and Mach, and Tyrus, and the sons of
Gomar, Ashkenazh, and Rifath, and
Togamar, and the sons of Jan, Elisha,
and Tarsus, Kdum, and Dodine. By these
were the owls of the Gentiles, divided
in their lands, everyone after his
tongue, after their families and their
nations.
Now they are the white man. They come
out of [__] Now let me show you where
Esau came. Let's go into Genesis the
25th chapter.
Let's start and read in verse 19.
Okay. Genesis 25:1 19 says, "And these
are the generations of Isaac." Abraham's
sons are Abraham's son. Abraham begat
Isaac. And Isaac was 40 years old when
he took Rebecca the wife and the
daughter of Bethuel, the Syrian of
Padanaram, the sister to Laban the
Syrian. And Isaac intreated the Lord for
his wife because she was barren. And the
Lord was entreated of him. And Rebecca
his wife conceived. And the children
struggled together within her. And she
said, "If it be so, why am I thus?" And
she went to inquire of the Lord. And the
Lord said unto her, "Two nations are in
thy womb. And two manner of people shall
be separated from thy boughs, and the
one people shall be stronger than the
other people, and the elders shall serve
the younger.
And when her days to be delivered were
fulfilled, behold, there were twins in
her womb, and the first came out red all
over like an hairy garment, and they
called his name Esau. And after that
came his came his brother out and his
hand took hold on Esau's heel and his
name was called Jacob. And Isaac was
three score years old when she bare
them.
So now Esau is not the white man the
gentile. He might look like him but Esau
is our twin brother. He is a Hebrew.
He's just not a Hebrew Israel.
Okay.
Yep.
And Jacob come out.
Jacob come out of She Esau
and Esau that mean that Esau came out of
shim.
The white man came out of [__] So when
you said that Esau is a is is this white
man a gentile, that's because you don't
have no biblical understanding.
That's all I have to say.
All right,
we like to thank everybody who tuned in
with us this evening from all around the
world. We had fun in dining on your
questions and we ask you that if you
submitted a question and we have a
chance to get to it, please don't
resubmit it cuz sister Deborah take it,
put it in rotation and we will deal with
that question next Wednesday. So until
we all come together again, be safe, be
blessed, stay prayed up, and may the
Lord have mercy on us all as brother
James closes us out.
Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name, thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread. And forgive us our debts as we
forgive our debtors. And lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom and the
power and the glory forever. In Jesus'
name we pray. Amen.